We'll be going through an image processing example in RGB and HSV color space.
接下来 我们要学习一个在 RGB 和 HSV 颜色空间中进行图像处理的案例
HSV color space isolates the Value or V component of each pixel in
HSV 颜色空间分离图像中每个像素的值或 V 分量
an image and this is the component that
这个分量在不同
varies the most under different lighting conditions.
光照条件下变化最大
The H or Hue channel stays fairly consistent under shadow or
H 或色调通道在阴影或高亮度条件下
excessive brightness and if we rely mainly on
非常稳定 如果我们主要依赖于
this channel and discard the information in the V channel,
这个通道 并丢弃 V 通道中的信息
we should be able to detect colored objects like
我们就能比 RGB 颜色空间更可靠地探测彩色对象
this green screen background more reliably than an RGB color space.
比如 这里的绿色屏幕背景
So, in this notebook,
因此 在这个笔记本中
I've imported the usual resources and read in an RGB image.
我已经导入了常用资源 并读入了一幅 RGB 图像
It's our green screen car, only this time,
绿色屏幕的汽车图像 但这次
it's lit unevenly, with shadow and areas of varying brightness.
亮度不均匀 带有阴影区域和亮度不同的区域
And I'll try to mask this green area looking at
我想遮罩这个绿色区域
both RGB color space and HSV to see what works in each case.
看看在 RGB 和 HSV 颜色空间中 是哪些通道起作用
Right now, each pixel in this image has an x and y value
现在 这幅图像中每个像素都有代表位置的 x 和 y 值
for its position and RGB values for its color.
以及代表代表颜色的 RGB 值
The first thing I'll do is recreate the RGB threshold that you've seen previously.
我首先要做的 是重建 RGB 阈值 这个之前学习过
So, to go over the steps again,
我们再过一遍
I create lower green and upper green thresholds in RGB color space.
我在 RGB 颜色空间中创建了绿色的下限和上限阈值
I create a mask using cv2.inRange and then I actually
使用 cv2.inRange 创建一个遮罩 然后
mask the portion of the image where the mask is not equal to zero where it's white,
遮盖遮罩面积不等于 0 的图像部分 即白色区域
and I'll display the image.
接下来 显示图像
Now this is using the exact same thresholds that we used in the previous case.
这里 我们使用的阈值和前一个案例中完全相同
Only this time, you can see that,
只是这次 你可以看到
because of the shadow,
由于阴影的存在
this only masks about half of the green screen background.
它只遮盖了一半的绿色屏幕背景
Let's see if we can do a little better in HSV color space.
我们看看 HSV 颜色空间是不是效果更好
First, I'll need to convert the image to HSV color space or use open cvCvtColor function,
首先 我需要把图像转换为 HSV 颜色空间 或使用 OpenCV 的 cvtColor 函数
which is a color conversion function and I'll use the conversion code RGB to HSV.
这是一个色彩转换函数 我使用 RGB 到 HSV 的转换代码
This will return a new converted image,
这样会返回一个转换后的图像
which I'll just call HSV.
我把它叫做 HSV
Then I'll actually isolate each of these channels of colors so that I can visualize them.
然后 我把每个色彩通道都隔离开 方便可视化
To isolate the Hue channel,
要隔离色调通道
I can just take the image array.
我只需代入图像阵列
I'll take all the x and y values in these first two array columns,
代入阵列前两列的 x 和 y 值
then the zero index of the third column which is the hue value for each pixel.
然后是第三列的 0 索引 代表每个像素的色调
Similarly, for saturation and value,
类似地 对于饱和度和明度 (value)
I'll take all the x and y coordinates of the image pixels and take
我打入图像像素的所有 x 和 y 坐标
the first and second index of the third column to get
然后取第三列的第一个和第二个索引
the saturation and value components of each pixel,
得到每个像素的饱和度和明度值
then I can plot each of these colored channels
然后在灰阶中绘制每个彩色通道
in grey scale to see their relative intensities.
查看它们的相对色饱和度
Here are the three channels represented in grey scale intensity.
这里是灰阶色饱和度表示的三个通道
The brighter pixels indicate higher values of Hue,
像素越亮 代表色调值
Saturation or Value respectively and we can see that even in shadow,
饱和度、明度的值越高 我们可以看到 即便在阴影部分
the hue level is pretty consistent.
色调水平仍然非常一致
But the saturation and value components vary a lot more especially under shadow.
但饱和度和明度分量变化很大 尤其是阴影部分
Now, you know how to create color thresholds and mask an image.
现在 你已经知道了如何创建色彩阈值并遮罩图像
Next, it will be up to you to use this information
接下来 你需要使用这些信息
and what you know about HSV color space to mask this image.
以及你的 HSV 知识来遮罩这幅图像
I won't show you my exact values,
我不会告诉你我的具体值
but I did use the Hue channel of HSV color space to mask
但的确使用了 HSV 颜色空间的色调通道
the green background for this image and you should be able to produce a similar result.
遮罩了这幅图像的绿色背景 你应该也能得出类似结果